[Music]
welcome to this watch new it's actually
watch old in a sense key updates in our
learning documentation for
developers in this session I'm going to
show you new guidance documentation in a
lot of places for Developers for Al
developers going through things like
data analytics reporting error handling
and so on so action-packed agenda let's
go the first thing is a new developer
documentation overview with its own doc
um AKA link so the new AKA link
aka.ms slbc developer takes you to this
session section in um in the
administration and Dev it pro
documentation I'll just quickly dive in
there and then we'll just keep it to
slides for the rest of this so that it's
going to be not so long and hopefully
less
boring all right so here is the new AKA
link and if I go there it takes me to
the development part of documentation
here um there are few things at least
for you to understand why we organize it
like this the first is that there is uh
things on getting started about the
development environment vs code and so
on um and then there are two very
similar sections here one is programming
in the AL language and the other one is
the AL programming language what's the
difference here well programming in the
AL language is a list of sections that
describe how to do various things and
many of these are related to the actual
data types in Al not necessarily the
language constructs the language
constructs is what you find in the a
programming language this is where we
explain things like what's a method how
to do for Loops or iterators variables
and so on and then there's a new kit on
the Block here uh data analytics and
Reporting um and extensibility um so
we'll show go a little bit into into
these top level uh topics so the first
topic new topic is data analytics for
developers this section is about how to
think about analytics for customers
because analytics is no no longer just
write a report and give it to the
customer there are many different
artifacts in analytics it could be a
query it could be data analysis on a
list or query it could be a powerbi
report or an Excel layout layout AED
report and so on so all these different
ways to think about analytics is
explained in this new part of docs uh
why you would use one over the other and
uh then with links to how to actually do
each of them so go check that out if you
if you work with with customer anal
analytics the second topic is reporting
in general reporting so we gave the
reporting document a a huge right
through hopefully everything that you
that you need is covered under this
developing report section everything you
need from how to deal with reports
basically anything we know that there is
to reporting in general so um go check
that out um at least know what's there
so that uh because I think you would you
would notice that a lot of the things
back from Seaside days has evolved a lot
over the
years and in particular word layouts
also got a huge over overhaul in
documentation so there's a new uh new
article on everything related to
document reporting with word layouts
anything on uh from how to design data
sets that works well with word word
layouts how to lay out different things
actually all the questions you have had
on how to do things with word should be
here uh so go check this out if if word
layout was kind of a mystery before I'm
pretty sure that you would find a lot of
new useful things and hopefully this
will also help you transition from RDL
uh into a word uh layout World in
particular for uh for document
reports a huge topic uh for stability is
error handling and uh for error handling
we also added a new section with
everything you need to know when
reasoning over errors and the first
article here is exactly that reasoning
about errors so think about how how to
do failure modeling how to do robust
coding a lot of the reference articles
in in docs actually was changed with
robust coding practice in mind so they
have examples of how to use a particular
method and code robust for it uh this
also has part have things on
understanding uh the error dialogue call
Stacks or stack traces how to do
actionable errors how to have error make
error messages that are meaningful to
the user and so
on so if you could if you could not
deflect an error situation with a good
error message or error handling
troubleshooting would be the next next
thing to look into and uh there's a new
troubleshooting uh overview part of of
the documentation that both give you an
indication or an idea of the different
tools you have for troubleshooting as
well as new content on what we call tsgs
or troubleshooting guides in many
different areas so go check the
troubleshooting guides out and also the
troubleshooting Tools in case you need
to troubleshoot something for a
customer when thinking about performance
perceived performance is a key thing
because it might be that you cannot make
something go faster make the time
shorter but maybe you can delegate that
to run in the background and that's what
we mean when we talk about as swing
processing so there's a new overview
here on the different ways to do it uh
you can spin off a new session page page
background tasks task scheduler job
queue and so on what's the difference
between these and with links to the
documentation for them all of that is is
here in this running things in the
background
section Telemetry is not only for people
in the basement is also a tool for you
as a developer and the section for
Telemetry for for Al developers has also
gotten some love so we added new content
on describing what's the difference
between this um scope of of telemetry
give more um we added more uh visibility
to the feature Telemetry module which is
a way for you within the system
application to get a lot of telemetry
features for free so go check that out
uh that might be new things that you
didn't know about Telemetry for
instrumenting your
app security is not only for the admin
it's also for you as developer you need
to think security into your app as well
so we added a new section for for how to
handle security or business Central
Security for a developers thinking about
or reasoning about the way you think in
Security in your development life cycle
and then going through all the topics
that we think is needed for you as
developer to De to deliver secure apps
for your customers so go check that
out
extensibility that's not only just like
a report extension and so on we we
thought that extensibility extensibility
is is everything that is related to as a
customer you don't care about how things
were uh extended so therefore we added
uh in the new extensibility overview
ways to extend in Al but also think
about extensibility as a way if you
extend the app by uh making changes to
the or suggest changes to the system
foundational layer system app or or the
the base app that's also a way to extend
it's just a way to extend where everyone
else gets your extension uh client
extensions using powerbi to extend all
of the the all the ways we think of of
of how you can extend business Central
for a customer is here in the
extensibility
overview finally um all of this docks
would would not be here all these
changes would not be there if you didn't
tell us about them and you might have
some expertise about a particular area
where docks could be better why not
simply do a pull request to that and the
way best way I find uh to the way to get
started is simply to search in in docs
for contribute that takes you to the or
find that that helps you find the
contribute to the help article and this
uh this takes you through how to work
with GitHub how to do a pull requests
and and contribute to the
documentation so Goos for you as a
developer U learn the new AKA link uh
aka.ms BC developer and if you start
something new go to docs to start your
learning I'm pretty sure that it it has
the introduction level content that you
need and if in doubt also go to docs
because we do a lot of work to make sure
that whenever you have a question on how
things work or maybe how things doesn't
work if you think about robustness it it
should be in docs so so so go to docs
and see if if it's not already covered
you can just search
um in in the learn portal as an expert
as I mentioned if there's something you
know that isn't there consider do a PR
to help others if all the experts in the
world do that um we might have a docs
that is uh just so rich that it it helps
uh everyone and uh if there's something
in docs completely missing where you
don't have the courage to do a a doc PR
let us know and uh then we know where to
improve
that's it other relevant launch event
sessions if you are in this thinking
about as as an a developer High chance
that you also want to look at uh the the
new what's new on uh invis Studio code
and Al development uh there's a a sister
a sister presentation to this for people
working with Integrations a lot of key
updates to the documentation on how
business Central integrates to the world
including uh web services if you are
more into the AL runtime Parts there's a
new what's new session on Al runtime and
database what's new for web service
functionality and also for reporting
which in this semester we gave a lot of
love to excel
layouts as always AKA links to learn
more if you have a question go to Yammer
BC Yammer uh BC all is the AKA link to
rule them all this is the one that takes
you and shows you all the AKA links that
exists for a for a developer or partner
and BC ideas is of course where you
suggest uh functionality changes uh to
business Central there are a number of
social media platform we are on X and on
LinkedIn and uh there are office hours
both live where you can attend and uh
you can watch the recording so go check
that out if you have something where you
have an interest in in one of these
recordings that's it thank you so much
and have a great launch
event